>> Jem Young: 好的，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: All right,
我们提到的另一件事就是所谓的许可
another thing we we touched on
is something called permissions.
所以许可权的类型基于这个想法，最终可能有人会
So permissions kind of are based on this
idea that eventually someone probably will
进入你的服务器
get into your server.
这并不是真的，但它是从这些线条中思考的。
That's not actually true, but
it's kind of thinking along those lines.
许可权意味着您正在锁定可对文件执行的操作。
Permissions mean you're locking
down what you can do with a file.
还有那些事我要问你
And those things, actually I'll ask you,
你能用档案做什么
what are the things you
can do with a file?
而且只有三种东西，它们是非常基本的。
And there's only three things,
and they're pretty fundamental.
怎么了 >> 扬声器 2: 读，写，执行。
Yes?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Read, write, execute.
>> Jem Young: 确实，您可以读取文件，可以写入文件，并且
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Exactly, you can read
a file, you can write to a file, and
如果它是某种程序，那么您可以执行该文件，并且
you can execute that file if
it's some sort of program, and
许可权都是关于控制的。
permissions are all
about controlling that.
比如说我们什么都是用 sudo 的，因为我们没有权限
For instance, we use sudo for everything
because we don't have permission
修改，比如说，防火墙之类的。
to modify, say, the firewall or
something like that.
所以我们用超级用户的力量来做到这一点。
So we're using the super
user power to do that.
这意味着如果有人来我的服务器
Which means if someone
came into my server and
他们不知道我的 sudo 密码还会惹麻烦
they don't know my sudo password they
can still cause a lot of trouble.
但他们的爆炸半径非常有限因为他们没有
But they're gonna be very limited in their
blast radius because they don't have that
路由许可权，这几乎完全忽略所有许可权。
route permission, which pretty much
ignores all of the permissions.
因此，我们有这样的文件许可权概念。
So we have this concept
of file permissions.
昨天我们修改了授权密钥文件
Yesterday we modified our authorized
key file to be readable and
只能由我们和超级用户写，因为我们不希望有人进来
writable by only us and the super user
because we don't want people coming in and
修改该密钥文件 ( 如果他们无权访问我的帐户或 root 帐户) 。
modifying that key file if they don't have
access to my account or the root account.
我提到解码，我们使用的数字是一种手杖。
And I mentioned that the decode, the
numbers that we use are kind of arcane.
有一个转换可对我的可读和可写操作进行转换
There is a conversion that converts
what's readable and writable to my
用户与 root 用户相比，但我已经查过一次，这很复杂。
user versus the root user, but I've looked
it up once and it's really complicated.
所以你最好记住你只需要的那些
So it's better just to memorize
the ones that you only need.
我说这很有诱惑力
I'll say this, it's really tempting.
您可能看到了使用 chmod 命令的代码示例。
You've probably seen code examples
to use the chmod command.
这就是变更修改，这意味着文件的许可权。
So that's change modification,
which means permissions for a file.
而且很容易就能读完这件事
And it's really easy just to be,
well, I need this file to be read and
我现在无权这么做所以我想去执行它
I don't have permission to do it right
now so I'm trying to execute it.
而且只能由超级用户执行
And that can only be executed
by the super user so
我要把它做 chmod 777
I'm just going to make it chmod 777.
那是你一直看到的那就是最出名的
That's one you see all the time, and
that's what's known as the laziest
许可权，因为它意味着您不必考虑许可权。
permission because it means you don't
have to think about permissions.
这对每个人都是开放的
It's just open to everybody.
你不应该做 777 除非你真的知道自己在做什么
You shouldn't do 777 unless you
really know what you're doing or,
我不会说你太着急了，你太坏了。
I won't say you're in a hurry,
cuz [LAUGH] that's so bad.
但如果你急着要去执行一个剧本
But if you're in a hurry and
you're trying to execute a script and
它没有安全的影响你可以用 777 但是你一般都不知道
it has no security ramifications you
can use 777, but you generally don't.
我们不会做太多的工作但是
We're not gonna do too
much with permissions, but
如果你想看看他们
if you wanna take a look at them.
假设我们在家里的目录里没什么大事
Let's say we're in our home directory,
there's nothing major.
所以我们可以说，它会告诉我所有读，写的权限。
So we can say ls -la and it's gonna tell
me all the permissions for read, write.
所以它是读，写，执行自己，读，写，为我的组执行，
And so it's read, write, execute for
myself, read, write, execute for my group,
是 sudo，读，写，执行每个人。
which is sudo, and read,
write, execute for everyone.
这就是你的权限
And that's what the permissions,
我真的希望他们能把 chmod 映射到这里的实际命令，但它们不会。
I really wish they would map chmod to
the actual commands here but they don't.
所以你要记住其中的一些。
So you just have to memorize some of them.
但如果你看到 777 它会被读出来
But if you see 777 it's gonna be read,
写，跨所有板执行。
write, execute across the board for
everything.
别用那个了
Just don't use that one.
其实我只会查个男人的 chmod
And actually, I'll just look up man chmod.
>> Jem Young: 更改文件方式位，是。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Change file mode bits, yeah.
>> Jem Young: 可以在午饭时给我们的奖金
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Maybe for
a bonus trivia over lunch we can look up
4 到许可权级别的映射。
what exactly maps like a four
to the permission level.
有一个映射，它只是不直观。
And there is a mapping,
it just is not intuitive.
>> Jem Young: 但总的来说，你一直想对你的档案拥有最少的信任。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But in general, you always
wanna have the least trust for your file.
所以如果一个团体或者
So if a group or
用户不需要专门访问文件，只需将其锁定。
user doesn't need to specifically
access a file, just lock it down.
您希望尽可能少的许可权
You want to have the least
permissions as possible
以防有人进入你的服务器
just in case someone
gets into your server.
或者从 DevOps的角度来考虑案例。
Or think of a case in terms of DevOps.
如果您正在为大量用户运行服务器，那么您不希望它们能够
If you're running a server for lots of
users, you don't want them to be able to
为每个用户启用许可权，因为其中一个用户可能要
enable permissions for everybody because
one of those users is probably gonna
有不好的密码之类的或者坏的钥匙被偷了
have a bad password or something like
that or a bad key that got stolen.
如果有人这样说的话
And if someone breaks in with that,
你希望他们能做最少的损失
you want them to be able to do
the least amount of damage.